<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
   Auto-generated using docbuilder.js. Do not edit manually. 
-->
<page xmlns="http://tjansen.de/minifiedPage" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://tjansen.de/minifiedPage ../schemas/page.xsd ">
	<title>.on() - Minified.js</title>
	<section>reference</section>
	<main>
<p><a href="index.html">back to Overview</a></p>
<h3><a name="doc-on">.on()</a></h3>
<div class="summary">Registers the function as event handler for all items in the list.</div>

<h4>Syntax</h4>
<div class="syntaxVariant">
<div class="syntax">MINI(selector).on(el, name, handler)</div>
<div class="syntax">MINI(selector).on(el, name, handler, args)</div>
<div class="syntax">MINI(selector).on(el, name, handler, args, fThis)</div>
</div>

<h4>Parameters</h4>
<dl class="params">
<dt id="on_name"><a name="on_name">name</a></dt>
<dd>the name of the event, e.g. 'click'. Case-sensitive. The 'on' prefix in front of the name must not used.</dd>
<dt id="on_handler"><a name="on_handler">handler</a></dt>
<dd>the function(event, extraEvent) to invoke when the event has been triggered. If no arguments have been given,
the handler gets the original event object as first parameter and the compatibility object as second.
'this' is always the element that caused the event.
Unless the handler returns true, all further processing of the event will be stopped.
Minified will not use directly add this handler to the element, but create a wrapper that will eventually invoke it. The wrapper
is added to the handler in a property called 'M'.</dd>
<dt id="on_args"><a name="on_args">args</a></dt>
<dd><span class="optional">optional</span> if set an array of arguments to pass to the handler function instead of the event objects</dd>
<dt id="on_fThis"><a name="on_fThis">fThis</a></dt>
<dd>an optional value for 'this' in the handler, as alternative to the event target</dd>
<dt id="on_RETURN" class="returnValue"><a name="on_RETURN">return value</a></dt>
<dd>the list</dd>
</dl>

<h4>Description</h4>
<div class="description">Registers the function as event handler for all items in the list.

By default, handlers get a the original event object and minified's compatibility event object as arguments, and 'this' set to the source element
of the event (e.g. the button that has been clicked). The original event object the is object given to the event or obtained
from 'window.event'. The compatibility event object has the following properties:
<ul>
<li><code>key</code> - the key code, if it was a key press. Will return event.keyCode if set, otherwise event.which. This should work in practically all browsers.
                                             See http://unixpapa.com/js/key.html for key code tables.</li>
<li><code>right</code> - true if the right mouse button has been clicked, false otherwise. Works browser-independently.</li>
<li><code>pageX</code> - the page coordinate of the event</li>
<li><code>pageY</code> - the page coordinate of the event</li>
</ul>
Unless the handler returns 'true', the event will not be propagated to other handlers.

Instead of the event objects, you can also pass an array of arguments and a new value for 'this' to the event handler. When you pass arguments, the
handler's return value is always ignored and the event will always be cancelled.

</div>

<div class="examples">
<h4>Example</h4>
<div class="example">Adds a simple click handler to a button. Event objects are ignored.
<pre>
$('#myButton').on('click', function() {
   window.alert('Button clicked!');
});
</pre>
</div>
<h4>Example</h4>
<div class="example">Adds a handler to all divs that paints their background color to red when clicked.
<pre>
$('div').on('click', function() {
   this.style.backgroundColor = 'red';    // 'this' contains the element that caused the event
});
</pre>
</div>
<h4>Example</h4>
<div class="example">Adds an handler for mousedown events to a canvas:
<pre>
var ctx = $$('#myCanvas').getContext('2d');                      // get a canvas context
$('#myCanvas').on('mousedown', function(evt, extraInfo) {        // add handler for mouse down events
    if (extraInfo.right)                                         // right mouse button paints white, all other black
        ctx.fillStyle = "white";
    else
        ctx.fillStyle = "black";
    ctx.fillRect(evt.clientX, evt.clientY, 1, 1);                // paints a pixel at the cursor position
});
</pre>
</div>
</div>


<p><a href="index.html">back to Overview</a></p>
	</main>
</page>
