<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
   Auto-generated using docbuilder.js. Do not edit manually. 
-->
<page xmlns="http://tjansen.de/minifiedPage" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://tjansen.de/minifiedPage ../schemas/page.xsd ">
	<title>.wire() - Minified.js</title>
	<section>reference</section>
	<main>
<p><a href="index.html">back to Overview</a></p>
<h3><a name="doc-wire">.wire()</a></h3>
<div class="summary">
Sets up events that will trigger the given toggles.</div>

<h4>Syntax</h4>
<div class="syntaxVariant">
<div class="syntax">MINI(selector).wire(events, toggles)</div>
</div>

<h4>Parameters</h4>
<dl class="params">
<dt id="wire_events"><a name="wire_events">events</a></dt>
<dd>either a simple string if the list element is the only element to wire. Then it contains a space-separated list of event names (e.g. 'click', 'mouseover').
By default the event toggles, unless it is prefixed with a '-' or '+'. If prefixed, the event will set the toggle to the first state for '-' or the
or the second state for '+'.
Alternatively, events can contain a map of selectors as keys which describe the triggering element and values that describe the events using the string
syntax shown above. Selectors are executed in the list element's context, unless they start with a '#'.</dd>
<dt id="wire_toggles"><a name="wire_toggles">toggles</a></dt>
<dd>describes the toggle functions that will be triggered by the events. This parameter can be a single toggle function, a list of toggle functions,
a list of parameters for toggle() which will be used to create a new toggle, a string that will be used as single parameter for toggle(),
or a map whose keys are selector describing the elements to toggle and whose values describe the toggle using any of the previous ways to
define a toggle.</dd>
<dt id="wire_RETURN" class="returnValue"><a name="wire_RETURN">return value</a></dt>
<dd>the list</dd>
</dl>

<h4>Description</h4>
<div class="description">
Sets up events that will trigger the given toggles.

The first arguments sets up which kind of events will trigger the toggles in what way. There are two ways to specify the events:
<ul>
<li>A simple string in the form "eventtype +eventtype -eventtype" adds the space-separated event handlers for each list member. Non-prefixed
    event types toggle. If prefixed with + or -, they will put the toggles in the first or second state.</li>
<li>A map allows you to add events to more than one element. They map key specifies the selector to find the element. The map value specifies the
    events in the form described above.</li>
</ul>

The second argument describes the toggles that are controlled by the events. If you pass a simple toggle function or a list of toggle function,
they will be simply called. You can also specify an array of parameters to the toggle() function to create new toggles for each list member.
The most powerful form of argument is a map containing selectors as first and toggle() arrays as values. This will set up new toggles for each
list member.

The selectors given in the event and toggle maps are always executed in the context of the current list elements, unless they start with a '#'. In
the latter case, they will be executes in the document context. If you pass a 0 (or any other value evaluating to false), the value applies to the list
member itself.

</div>

<div class="examples">
<h4>Example</h4>
<div class="example">Wires the list members to change the text color of the element 'colorChanger' on click:
<pre>
var tog = $('#colorChanger').toggle({$color: 'red'}, {$color: 'blue'});
$('.clicky').wire('click', tog);
</pre>
</div>
<h4>Example</h4>
<div class="example">Wires the list members to change their own text color on click:
<pre>
$('.clicky').wire('click', [{$color: 'red'}, {$color: 'blue'}]);
</pre>
</div>
<h4>Example</h4>
<div class="example">Wires the list members to change their own text color to blue on mouseover and red otherwise:
<pre>
$('.mouseovers').wire('-mouseout +mouseover', [{$color: 'red'}, {$color: 'blue'}]);
</pre>
</div>
<h4>Example</h4>
<div class="example">Same mouse over effect as in the previous example, but wires element '#allBlueButton' to change the color of all elements to blue on click:
<pre>
$('.mouseovers').wire({'': '-mouseout +mouseover', '#allBlueButton': '+click'}
                  [{$color: 'red'}, {$color: 'blue'}]);
</pre>
</div>
<h4>Example</h4>
<div class="example">Wires a dropdown menu. Its toggle modifies the CSS class of the 'dropdown.
<pre>
$('.dropdown').wire({'.head': 'click', '.closeButton': '-click'} , [{$: '-shown'}, {$: '+shown'}]);
</pre>
</div>
<h4>Example</h4>
<div class="example">wire() also supports single strings as argument for the toggle to modify only CSS classes. The following
         example does the same as the preceding one.
<pre>
$('.dropdown').wire({'.head': 'click', '.closeButton': '-click'} , 'shown');
</pre>
</div>
</div>


<p><a href="index.html">back to Overview</a></p>
	</main>
</page>
